<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services-2s on Mark Richman</title>
    <link>https://markrichman.com/services-2/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services-2s on Mark Richman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. Mark Richman Consulting, Inc. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 15:58:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://markrichman.com/services-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Services-old</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/services-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 15:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/services-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;application-portfolio-reviews&#34;&gt;Application Portfolio Reviews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I perform comprehensive reviews of IT application portfolios, assisting management in justifying and measuring the business benefits of each application in comparison to the costs of ongoing maintenance and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a focus on Cloud Computing alternatives to traditional backoffice applications, I offer actionable plans for IT and business alignment by reducing costs, risks and unlocking potential for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-capex-and-opex-reviews&#34;&gt;IT CapEx and OpEx Reviews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the single best possible reasons for large companies to switch to the SaaS model is a switch from IT capital expenditures (CapEx) and a move towards IT operational expenses (OpEx). IT CapEx is money spent on acquiring physical assets for the purpose of running your business. OpEx is money spent on the operational aspect of running your business. IT CapEx tends to be less fluid and much more expensive than routine IT OpEx. CapEx spending also tends to be harder to forecast than OpEx. OpEx typically represents a real cost of doing business: your business needs an internet connection to exist, and you pay for what you use. CapEx in general is often more fuzzy in relation to its impact on a company’s operations, especially when it comes to IT CapEx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I provide in-depth analysis of your IT CapEx and provide recommendations to move all or part of those expenditures to OpEx using Cloud Computing technologies such as Software-as-a-Service (SaaS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-headcount-rationalization&#34;&gt;IT Headcount Rationalization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When planning a Cloud Computing migration, headcount rationalization should be completed to keep the team focused during the transition phase, and a time-phased staffing plan of the future operating structure should be defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I provide tactical and strategic direction on the changing roles and size of your IT staff as you move to Cloud Computing technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dr-analysis&#34;&gt;DR Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many businesses rely on Disaster Recovery (DR) services to prevent either manmade or natural disasters from causing expensive service disruptions. Unfortunately, current DR services come either at very high cost, or with only weak guarantees about the amount of data lost or time required to restart operation after a failure. Cloud Computing is well suited for offering DR as a service due to pay-as-you-go pricing models that can lower costs, and the use of automated virtual platforms that can minimize the recovery time after a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work with clients to analyze and transition their DR plan to the cloud, demonstrating significant cost, risk, and downtime reductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;application-architecture&#34;&gt;Application Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I design complex infrastructures for highly secure, scalable, and fault-tolerant systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;web-and-mobile-application-development&#34;&gt;Web and Mobile Application Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I create custom web and mobile applications, specializing in Ruby on Rails and ASP.NET&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>