<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Mark Richman</title>
    <link>https://markrichman.com/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Mark Richman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. Mark Richman Consulting, Inc. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1900 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markrichman.com/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Web Services (AWS) Migration</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/services/aws-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1900 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/services/aws-migration/</guid>
      <description>I can help you transform your business and deliver high-performing applications, faster and more economically than with on-premises solutions. My Amazon Web Services (AWS) migration services include: strategy and roadmap, infrastructure audit, architecture design, automation, deployment, testing, cutover and disaster recovery planning.
Migrating a single application to AWS can seem simple. Sometimes it is. But more often, that application’s function is tied to multiple business processes and dependencies. It may impact your vendors, your balance sheet, your regulatory compliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/services/index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1900 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/services/index/</guid>
      <description>How Mark Can Help You Mark Richman works with clients to develop the people, processes, technologies, skills, and strategies required to achieve tactical objectives and strategic goals.
Mark offers a unique combination of deep technical and business expertise, and a strong track record of success. Mark has built, grown, and driven software engineering teams for organizations of all sizes.
Cloud Strategy Retainer Cloud-based applications are not simply “forklifted” versions of their on-premises cousins; in fact, cloud application platforms are far more sophisticated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Retainer</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/services/strategy-retainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1900 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/services/strategy-retainer/</guid>
      <description>Cloud-based applications are not simply “forklifted” versions of their on-premises cousins; in fact, cloud application platforms are far more sophisticated.
Learning things the hard way in the cloud means wasting tens (or sometimes hundreds) of thousands of dollars on misguided development efforts. Worse, you risk losing valuable competitive advantage by prolonging your time to market. Our consulting engagement will give you access to the strategic and tactical cloud expertise you need, when you need it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>