<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Mark Richman</title>
    <link>https://markrichman.com/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Mark Richman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. Mark Richman Consulting, Inc. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 15:45:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markrichman.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservative vs. Liberal</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/conservative-vs-liberal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 15:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/conservative-vs-liberal/</guid>
      <description>If a conservative doesn&amp;#8217;t like guns, he doesn&amp;#8217;t buy one.
If a liberal doesn&amp;#8217;t like guns, he wants all guns outlawed.
If a conservative is a vegetarian, he doesn&amp;#8217;t eat meat.
If a liberal is a vegetarian, he wants all meat products banned for everyone.
If a conservative sees a foreign threat, he thinks about how to defeat his enemy.
A liberal wonders how to surrender gracefully and still look good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorry, Mom. I’m a Republican.</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/sorry-mom-im-a-republican/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/sorry-mom-im-a-republican/</guid>
      <description>I thought this piece (Weineg, 2004) was so &amp;#8220;on the money&amp;#8221;, four years ago, that I am reposting it again this election year&amp;#8230;and again on my mom&amp;#8217;s birthday 🙂 Happy Birthday, Mom!
&amp;#8220;Growing up as an upper-middle class, Jewish boy in New York City, I had almost no other choice than to pretend to be a liberal. My high school was a hippie nest. Instead of Fs, I got hugs if I didn&amp;#8217;t know how to spell my name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Republican Party</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/welcome-to-the-republican-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 21:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/welcome-to-the-republican-party/</guid>
      <description>A young woman was about to finish her first year of college. Like so many others her age, she considered herself to be a very liberal Democrat, and among other liberal ideals, was very much in favor of higher taxes to support more government programs, in other words, redistribution of wealth.
She was deeply ashamed that her father was a rather staunch Republican, a feeling she openly expressed. Based on the lectures that she had participated in, and the occasional chat with a professor, she felt that her father had for years harbored an evil, selfish desire to keep what he thought should be his.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>