<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Richman Consulting</title>
    <link>http://www.markrichman.com/tags/politics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mark Richman Consulting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016 Mark Richman Consulting, Inc. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://www.markrichman.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservative vs. Liberal</title>
      <link>http://www.markrichman.com/conservative-vs-liberal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 15:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>http://www.markrichman.com/conservative-vs-liberal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If a conservative doesn&amp;#8217;t like guns, he doesn&amp;#8217;t buy one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a liberal doesn&amp;#8217;t like guns, he wants all guns outlawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative is a vegetarian, he doesn&amp;#8217;t eat meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a liberal is a vegetarian, he wants all meat products banned for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative sees a foreign threat, he thinks about how to defeat his enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A liberal wonders how to surrender gracefully and still look good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative is homosexual, he quietly leads his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a liberal is homosexual, he demands legislated respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a black man or Hispanic are conservative, they see themselves as independently successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their liberal counterparts see themselves as victims in need of government protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative is down-and-out, he thinks about how to better his situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A liberal wonders who is going to take care of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative doesn&amp;#8217;t like a talk show host, he switches channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberals demand that those they don&amp;#8217;t like be shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative is a non-believer, he doesn&amp;#8217;t go to church/temple/mosque.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A liberal non-believer wants any mention of G-d and religion silenced. (Unless it&amp;#8217;s a foreign religion, of course!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative decides he needs health care, he goes about shopping for it, or may choose a job that provides it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A liberal demands that the rest of us pay for his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative slips and falls in a store, he gets up, laughs and is embarrassed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a liberal slips and falls, he grabs his neck, moans like he&amp;#8217;s in labor and then sues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a conservative reads this, he&amp;#8217;ll forward it so his friends can have a good laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A liberal will delete it because he&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;offended.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorry, Mom. I’m a Republican.</title>
      <link>http://www.markrichman.com/sorry-mom-im-a-republican/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>http://www.markrichman.com/sorry-mom-im-a-republican/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought this piece (Weineg, 2004) was so &amp;#8220;on the money&amp;#8221;, four years ago, that I am reposting it again this election year&amp;#8230;and again on my mom&amp;#8217;s birthday 🙂 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy Birthday, Mom!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Growing up as an upper-middle class, Jewish boy in New York City, I had almost no other choice than to pretend to be a liberal. My high school was a hippie nest. Instead of Fs, I got hugs if I didn&amp;#8217;t know how to spell my name. I was given detention if I didn&amp;#8217;t smoke pot in the park between classes. And did you know that Rush Limbaugh and Daddy Bush actually are spawns of Satan? And what&amp;#8217;s worse, I bought it. Well, I mean, why not? I&amp;#8217;ve gotta tell you, being a liberal is cool! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was liberal, I didn&amp;#8217;t pay any taxes. No way, baby. That&amp;#8217;s a job for the rich. I was all for a severe cut, if not complete elimination of taxes. Besides, we could afford to cut costs on some of the wasteful government programs around today, like the military, for example. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was liberal, I didn&amp;#8217;t have to pay for anything. I mean, come on. I&amp;#8217;m an American citizen. I should be getting free health care, free education, free room and board, whatever I need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else? When I was a liberal, I used common-sense on matters of national security. I mean, who needs this &amp;#8220;war on terror&amp;#8221; when I am way more likely to die from a car crash than from a terrorist attack? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, and not for lack of effort, I caved. I wanted so badly to live in your utopia, where capitalism and communism share meaning, and free speech reigns as long as it is not exercised by the likes of such filthy rich, bigoted white guys as Rupert Murdoch and Rush Limbaugh or used to print the evil Northwestern Chronicle. However, this is when I started to think that maybe I&amp;#8217;m beginning to head down the wrong path. I realized that instead of praising the foundation that has created this great country, I was being taught to fight against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to liberal idealism, it should be the job of government to provide a good economic environment for each and every member of society to protect our citizens from making bad economic decisions or choices. Capitalism is the seed that made this country what it is today, but from a liberal viewpoint, capitalism is inherently evil because it leads to an unequal distribution of wealth. I think you get where I&amp;#8217;m going with this &amp;#8230; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, after a lifetime of living on the Left, I now find myself as an editor for the Chronicle and therefore one of the few public, outspoken conservatives on campus. That said, I&amp;#8217;m still an upper-middle class, Jewish boy from New York City. It&amp;#8217;s just I can no longer believe liberal lies that socialism is right and America is wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sorry, Mom; I&amp;#8217;m a Republican. I can&amp;#8217;t exactly say where you messed up. However, my ballot is going to differ from yours come November. But still, how do I justify that I&amp;#8217;m voting for Bush? I don&amp;#8217;t criticize our president because he suggested Americans should put food on their families. Instead, I realize how much better off we are as a country, how much safer we are because of the Republicans.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weineg, J. (2004). Sorry, Mom, I&amp;#8217;m a Republican. _Northwestern Chronicle, _May 2, 2004. Retrieved October 5, 2004 from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chron.org/tools/viewart.php?artid=931&#34;&gt;http://www.chron.org/tools/viewart.php?artid=931&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Republican Party</title>
      <link>http://www.markrichman.com/welcome-to-the-republican-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 21:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>http://www.markrichman.com/welcome-to-the-republican-party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A young woman was about to finish her first year of college. Like so many others her age, she considered herself to be a very liberal Democrat, and among other liberal ideals, was very much in favor of higher taxes to support more government programs, in other words, redistribution of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was deeply ashamed that her father was a rather staunch Republican, a feeling she openly expressed. Based on the lectures that she had participated in, and the occasional chat with a professor, she felt that her father had for years harbored an evil, selfish desire to keep what he thought should be his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day she was challenging her father on his opposition to higher taxes on the rich and the need for more government programs. The self-professed objectivity proclaimed by her professors had to be the truth and she indicated so to her father. He responded by asking how she was doing in school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken aback, she answered rather haughtily that she had a 4.0 GPA, and let him know that it was tough to maintain, insisting that she was taking a very difficult course load and was constantly studying, which left her no time to go out and party like other people she knew. She didn&amp;#8217;t even have time for a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;boyfriend, and didn&amp;#8217;t really have many college friends because she spent all her time studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her father listened and then asked, &amp;#8216;How is your friend Audrey doing?&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She replied, &amp;#8216;Audrey is barely getting by. All she takes are easy classes, she never studies, and she barely has a 2.0 GPA. She is so popular on campus; college for her is a blast. She&amp;#8217;s always invited to all the parties and lots of times she doesn&amp;#8217;t even show up for classes because she&amp;#8217;s too hung over.&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her wise father asked his daughter, &amp;#8216;Why don&amp;#8217;t you go to the Dean&amp;#8217;s office and ask him to deduct 1.0 off your GPA and give it to your friend who only has a 2.0. That way you will both have a 3.0 GPA and certainly that would be a fair and equal distribution of GPA.&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The daughter, visibly shocked by her father&amp;#8217;s suggestion, angrily fired back,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8216;That&amp;#8217;s a crazy idea, how would that be fair! I&amp;#8217;ve worked really hard for my grades! I&amp;#8217;ve invested a lot of time, and a lot of hard work! Audrey has done next to nothing toward her degree. She played while I worked my tail off!&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The father slowly smiled, winked and said gently, &amp;#8216;Welcome to the Republican Party.&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>