<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consulting on Mark Richman</title>
    <link>https://markrichman.com/tags/consulting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consulting on Mark Richman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. Mark Richman Consulting, Inc. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 13:09:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markrichman.com/tags/consulting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Value-Based Fees for Agile Software Projects</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/thoughts-on-value-based-fees-for-agile-software-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 13:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/thoughts-on-value-based-fees-for-agile-software-projects/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#8217;s a quandary &amp;#8211; we, as value-based IT consultants, aspire to charge value-based fees for our services (how obvious!). We know that doing so requires tight scope control. As such, this often requires a detailed specification. However, this is the very waterfall model that the agile movement shuns. How do you reconcile scope control, customer satisfaction, and ever-changing requirements with value-based fees? I don&amp;#8217;t think it&amp;#8217;s preferable &amp;#8211; or practical &amp;#8211; to do two week iterations on a value-based fee basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evangelizing Yourself</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/evangelizing-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 17:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/evangelizing-yourself/</guid>
      <description>A phenomenally inspiring presentation by Whitney Hess from IA Summit 2009. This really hits home for me, as I&amp;#8217;m also a self-promoting introvert.
View more documents from Whitney Hess.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the Billable Hour part 3: Seven Industries</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/questioning-the-billable-hour-part-3-seven-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 00:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/questioning-the-billable-hour-part-3-seven-industries/</guid>
      <description>Situation A: Is Faster Service Worth More?
Your computer is not working properly. You have tried to understand the problem and find a solution that you can implement yourself. Yet, after trying, you are no closer to a solution, you find the situation aggravating, and you decide that there’s no point in continuing to attempt fixing the problem yourself. Your time and attention are better spent on productive activities and should not be wasted on this computer problem any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Never Bill by the Hour</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/why-i-never-bill-by-the-hour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 13:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/why-i-never-bill-by-the-hour/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;#8217;ve been reading my blog for any length of time, you know that I&amp;#8217;m an advocate of Value-Based Fees. In a nutshell, here is the value proposition to the prospective client:
 There is a cap on your investment. You know exactly what is to be spent and there are no surprises. There is never a &amp;#8220;meter running.&amp;#8221; You do not have to worry each time my help is requested that I might be here for an hour, a day, or a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining Value-Based Fees for Software Projects – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/determining-value-based-fees-for-software-projects-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/determining-value-based-fees-for-software-projects-part-3/</guid>
      <description>I followed up on David Winch&amp;#8217;s last points with some more of my own:  &amp;#8220;Now, all I need is a few prospects on whom to practice! But I&amp;#8217;m sure &amp;#8216;how do I find clients?&amp;#8217; is a huge component of your workshop, so I do not presume to receive such a detailed response to that one.  &amp;#8220;It is quite obvious to me now that I have been trying to sell not only what I do, but very specifically how I do it (right down to promoting my toolset of choice).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>