<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Richman</title>
    <link>/tags/consulting/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mark Richman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. Mark Richman Consulting, Inc. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/consulting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Value-Based Fees for Agile Software Projects</title>
      <link>/thoughts-on-value-based-fees-for-agile-software-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 13:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>/thoughts-on-value-based-fees-for-agile-software-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a quandary &amp;#8211; we, as value-based IT consultants, aspire to charge value-based fees for our services (how obvious!). We know that doing so requires tight scope control. As such, this often requires a detailed specification. However, this is the very &lt;a title=&#34;Waterfall Model&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterfall_model&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;waterfall model&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;a title=&#34;Agile Software Development&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;agile movement&lt;/a&gt; shuns. How do you reconcile &lt;a title=&#34;Scope Creep&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scope_creep&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scope control&lt;/a&gt;, customer satisfaction, and ever-changing requirements with value-based fees? I don&amp;#8217;t think it&amp;#8217;s preferable &amp;#8211; or practical &amp;#8211; to do two week iterations on a value-based fee basis. Just as much as value-based fees benefit the client by not requiring them to make an investment decision every time they wish to engage you, they also may trap the consultant into having a value discussion/negotiation with the client for each iteration. Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evangelizing Yourself</title>
      <link>/evangelizing-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 17:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>/evangelizing-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A phenomenally inspiring presentation by &lt;a title=&#34;Whitney Hess&#34; href=&#34;http://whitneyhess.com/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Whitney Hess&lt;/a&gt; from IA Summit 2009. This really hits home for me, as I&amp;#8217;m also a self-promoting introvert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;__ss_1184852&#34; style=&#34;width: 425px; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt; 
  
  &lt;div style=&#34;font-size: 11px; font-family: tahoma,arial; height: 26px; padding-top: 2px;&#34;&gt;
    View more &lt;a style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/&#34;&gt;documents&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/whitneyhess&#34;&gt;Whitney Hess&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the Billable Hour part 3: Seven Industries</title>
      <link>/questioning-the-billable-hour-part-3-seven-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 00:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>/questioning-the-billable-hour-part-3-seven-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation A: Is Faster Service Worth More?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your computer is not working properly. You have tried to understand the problem and find a solution that you can implement yourself. Yet, after trying, you are no closer to a solution, you find the situation aggravating, and you decide that there’s no point in continuing to attempt fixing the problem yourself. Your time and attention are better spent on productive activities and should not be wasted on this computer problem any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computer technician that you call asks a few questions then says to bring the computer in to his shop. He charges $60 per hour and predicts the computer ready in two business days. Once he has the computer, he will diagnose the problem then call you with an estimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; As you consider not having your computer on hand for two business days, and the opportunities to use it productively that you must forego, would you be willing to pay more to have it fixed and back in use much sooner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If the computer technician ****offered to fix your computer within 24 hours, satisfaction guaranteed, for a fixed fee agreed in advance, how attractive would that be to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation B: Evaluating Your Next Car&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You and your spouse are shopping for a new car. Having visited a few car dealers, conducted research on the web, and spoken to a trusted person at your usual auto-service shop, you and your spouse have narrowed your search to two cars, both of which you have taken on a test drive together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; As you consider the value of each car, do you care how quickly or slowly either car was built, or how much time the manufacturer put into design &amp;amp; engineering?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; As you consider the asking prices of the cars, does it matter to you how much time the car salesperson has spent on the sales process with you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation C: the Value of a Salad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a restaurant, you order a supper salad. The menu says that the salad costs $7.99. As usual, you expect the salad to be served to you in a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your order reaches the kitchen, the manager finds that the supply of tomatoes has gone too low. She sends somebody out to buy tomatoes so that your salad can include them. The errand runner breaks a sweat to get the tomatoes to the kitchen in time for your salad to be served with the rest of the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your salad is served with the rest of the meal, and it is billed at $7.99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; As you sit at your table waiting for your meal to be served (unaware of the restaurant’s tomato supply) does it matter to you if the kitchen’s supply of tomatoes has gone too low, causing the manager to send somebody out to buy more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If you knew about the low tomato supply and the decision to send somebody out to buy tomatoes, how would that affect your expectations about the timing of the meal being served or the amount billed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation D: How Much Trust When the Meter is Running?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacquie has been self-employed as a graphic designer for four years. She has found that her prospective clients (for example to design new logos and use those logos in designing stationery) typically start the buying process by asking her, “How much?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her first year, Jacquie found this frustrating because she could not answer right away. She needed to learn each client’s needs and expectations before she could provide a reasonable estimate, and her estimates were based on how much of her time would be needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, she learned to redirect that question to gauge the scope of each new project. This allowed her to provide reasonable estimates and close sales. Still, from that first question until the client signed her estimate, there was always uncomfortable uncertainty and a sense of risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There seemed to be a problem of trust intrinsic to the pricing aspect of the sales process. For example, one prospective client said, “I understand that you’ll show me three logo options with samples of how they’ll look on stationery. I am then supposed to choose and you’ll proceed from there. But what if I don’t like any of them as-is and want you to adjust or mix-and-match before I approve one? Would your fees stay the same?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacquie dreaded this. If the client was not satisfied with her initial work, then she would have to charge more or make less money for her time and effort. Under the circumstances, neither possibility was welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She considered that she would have to improve her skill at developing trust. She also longed for a way to make buying from her easier – especially if she could avoid the tension involved in estimating and hoping to make a decent profit when working for clients whose need for her billable time could exceed their budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; What if Jacquie reviews her process for each type of project to establish a range of cost? This way, somebody interested in a new logo and stationery, for example, could ask, “How much?” and Jacquie could reply, “It would cost between X and Y dollars. Let’s discuss what you’d get.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; What if, in addition to replying as above when asked, “How much?” Jacquie would say, “If we can discuss how important it is to you, then we can fix the fees in advance with a satisfaction guarantee”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation E: Paying for the Solution – Not the Time It Takes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dexter is a management consultant with an accounting firm. He has been advising the owners, directors, and senior managers of various companies long enough that he typically begins formulating solutions to their problems during the initial stage of discovering the problem. Understanding that each situation is unique, Dexter still pays close attention throughout the discovery stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because he always brings to bear his years of experience, and because he has the expertise to “sometimes come up with a $10,000 solution in 10 minutes,” Dexter eschews the billable hour as unfair. Rather, his firm charges fixed fees, established up-front based on the client’s gauge of importance, and includes a satisfaction guarantee. When the scope of any project changes while underway, the fee is adjusted on the same basis – all in writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; Would it still be more fair for Dexter’s firm to charge according to his time spent, with his rate per hour linked to his seniority?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; Should any other professions that apply experience and expertise to solve client problems also consider value-based fees, fixed up-front with a satisfaction guarantee, and accommodate any changes in scope by adjusting the fees?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation F: Fixing the Cost of a Pizza&lt;/strong&gt; ****&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Canada, there is a great number of pizzerias. Even small towns typically have more than one pizza place. Though there are pizza chains, there is also a variety of independent pizzerias across the country. Despite the number and variety, the industry has certain standards for ordering and pricing, anywhere you go, based on size of pizza and number of toppings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Emile considered opening a pizzeria in Morocco, he had the opportunity to consider the Canadian model: standard sizes of pizza, each with its own basic price, then standard pricing for toppings, plus free delivery within a certain radius. Emile analyzed the pizza business and found that toppings do vary in cost to the pizzeria. He also found that, with the overhead to keep a pizza oven at operating temperature, the cost to bake a pizza would vary with size each and number per day. The cost of any one ingredient could also vary over time, as would the price of fuel for a delivery car. These all factored into Emile’s business plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; How important is it to you to know how much a pizza will cost when you order it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If your pizza order today matches your pizza order from a month ago, do you consider it reasonable for the price to be the same, even if the pizzeria’s costs might have varied?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation G: Original, Custom Newsletters for Standard Prices&lt;/strong&gt; ****&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert was a professional writer, not of screenplays or magazine articles, but of original custom newsletters. Despite his ability as a wordsmith in a range of contexts, the market consistently regarded him as a newsletter specialist and brought that business to him. Robert decided to embrace this reputation. The rationale behind his business model was simple: Give people what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He developed a business model that would always create original, authentic newsletters – best to maintain a credible connection between his clients and their readers – and in an apparent paradox, make profits charging standardized fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reputation for newsletters that had driven demand for his writing was based on reliably good writing with a degree of original authenticity that made his third-party authorship invisible. He trained and managed a small cohort of writers in his techniques also so that readers would assume the writing to be the issuer’s. Robert also ensured that each newsletter would have a look unique to the issuer. Then, each issue would be laid out with client-approved text and photos by the same person who designed the original template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert paid his writers and designers fixed fees and had them work under a contract that protected the business interests of all parties. Likewise, he charged his clients fixed fees under a purchase agreement that both encouraged decisive collaboration on newsletter contents and allowed the flexibility necessary to make each issue fulfil its potential as a timely reflection of the issuer-reader relationship. His purchase agreement even included a pay-upon-approval satisfaction guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; If you could have original, custom work performed for you by a small team of creative people with the security of fixed fees and a satisfaction guarantee, would you bypass low-cost, off-the-shelf alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If you were to read a newsletter that seems to be a generic, impersonal product with the name and photo of an individual pasted in, would you consider it worth much more to that individual to issue an original, custom newsletter like those Robert and his team create?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Glenn R Harrington, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articulate.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Articulate Consultants Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glenn Harrington is the Principal Consultant of Articulate Consultants Inc. Since 1996 he has specialized in consulting on authentic key messages as the basis for effective marketing, brand management, and client loyalty.  []&lt;a href=&#34;href&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articulate.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articulate.ca/&#34;&gt;http://www.articulate.ca/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; []&lt;a href=&#34;href&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[]&lt;a href=&#34;href&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Situation A: Is Faster Service Worth More?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your computer is not working properly. You have tried to understand the problem and find a solution that you can implement yourself. Yet, after trying, you are no closer to a solution, you find the situation aggravating, and you decide that there’s no point in continuing to attempt fixing the problem yourself. Your time and attention are better spent on productive activities and should not be wasted on this computer problem any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computer technician that you call asks a few questions then says to bring the computer in to his shop. He charges $60 per hour and predicts the computer ready in two business days. Once he has the computer, he will diagnose the problem then call you with an estimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; As you consider not having your computer on hand for two business days, and the opportunities to use it productively that you must forego, would you be willing to pay more to have it fixed and back in use much sooner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If the computer technician ****offered to fix your computer within 24 hours, satisfaction guaranteed, for a fixed fee agreed in advance, how attractive would that be to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation B: Evaluating Your Next Car&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You and your spouse are shopping for a new car. Having visited a few car dealers, conducted research on the web, and spoken to a trusted person at your usual auto-service shop, you and your spouse have narrowed your search to two cars, both of which you have taken on a test drive together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; As you consider the value of each car, do you care how quickly or slowly either car was built, or how much time the manufacturer put into design &amp;amp; engineering?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; As you consider the asking prices of the cars, does it matter to you how much time the car salesperson has spent on the sales process with you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation C: the Value of a Salad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a restaurant, you order a supper salad. The menu says that the salad costs $7.99. As usual, you expect the salad to be served to you in a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your order reaches the kitchen, the manager finds that the supply of tomatoes has gone too low. She sends somebody out to buy tomatoes so that your salad can include them. The errand runner breaks a sweat to get the tomatoes to the kitchen in time for your salad to be served with the rest of the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your salad is served with the rest of the meal, and it is billed at $7.99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; As you sit at your table waiting for your meal to be served (unaware of the restaurant’s tomato supply) does it matter to you if the kitchen’s supply of tomatoes has gone too low, causing the manager to send somebody out to buy more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If you knew about the low tomato supply and the decision to send somebody out to buy tomatoes, how would that affect your expectations about the timing of the meal being served or the amount billed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation D: How Much Trust When the Meter is Running?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacquie has been self-employed as a graphic designer for four years. She has found that her prospective clients (for example to design new logos and use those logos in designing stationery) typically start the buying process by asking her, “How much?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her first year, Jacquie found this frustrating because she could not answer right away. She needed to learn each client’s needs and expectations before she could provide a reasonable estimate, and her estimates were based on how much of her time would be needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, she learned to redirect that question to gauge the scope of each new project. This allowed her to provide reasonable estimates and close sales. Still, from that first question until the client signed her estimate, there was always uncomfortable uncertainty and a sense of risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There seemed to be a problem of trust intrinsic to the pricing aspect of the sales process. For example, one prospective client said, “I understand that you’ll show me three logo options with samples of how they’ll look on stationery. I am then supposed to choose and you’ll proceed from there. But what if I don’t like any of them as-is and want you to adjust or mix-and-match before I approve one? Would your fees stay the same?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacquie dreaded this. If the client was not satisfied with her initial work, then she would have to charge more or make less money for her time and effort. Under the circumstances, neither possibility was welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She considered that she would have to improve her skill at developing trust. She also longed for a way to make buying from her easier – especially if she could avoid the tension involved in estimating and hoping to make a decent profit when working for clients whose need for her billable time could exceed their budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; What if Jacquie reviews her process for each type of project to establish a range of cost? This way, somebody interested in a new logo and stationery, for example, could ask, “How much?” and Jacquie could reply, “It would cost between X and Y dollars. Let’s discuss what you’d get.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;****&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; What if, in addition to replying as above when asked, “How much?” Jacquie would say, “If we can discuss how important it is to you, then we can fix the fees in advance with a satisfaction guarantee”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation E: Paying for the Solution – Not the Time It Takes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dexter is a management consultant with an accounting firm. He has been advising the owners, directors, and senior managers of various companies long enough that he typically begins formulating solutions to their problems during the initial stage of discovering the problem. Understanding that each situation is unique, Dexter still pays close attention throughout the discovery stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because he always brings to bear his years of experience, and because he has the expertise to “sometimes come up with a $10,000 solution in 10 minutes,” Dexter eschews the billable hour as unfair. Rather, his firm charges fixed fees, established up-front based on the client’s gauge of importance, and includes a satisfaction guarantee. When the scope of any project changes while underway, the fee is adjusted on the same basis – all in writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; Would it still be more fair for Dexter’s firm to charge according to his time spent, with his rate per hour linked to his seniority?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; Should any other professions that apply experience and expertise to solve client problems also consider value-based fees, fixed up-front with a satisfaction guarantee, and accommodate any changes in scope by adjusting the fees?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation F: Fixing the Cost of a Pizza&lt;/strong&gt; ****&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Canada, there is a great number of pizzerias. Even small towns typically have more than one pizza place. Though there are pizza chains, there is also a variety of independent pizzerias across the country. Despite the number and variety, the industry has certain standards for ordering and pricing, anywhere you go, based on size of pizza and number of toppings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Emile considered opening a pizzeria in Morocco, he had the opportunity to consider the Canadian model: standard sizes of pizza, each with its own basic price, then standard pricing for toppings, plus free delivery within a certain radius. Emile analyzed the pizza business and found that toppings do vary in cost to the pizzeria. He also found that, with the overhead to keep a pizza oven at operating temperature, the cost to bake a pizza would vary with size each and number per day. The cost of any one ingredient could also vary over time, as would the price of fuel for a delivery car. These all factored into Emile’s business plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; How important is it to you to know how much a pizza will cost when you order it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If your pizza order today matches your pizza order from a month ago, do you consider it reasonable for the price to be the same, even if the pizzeria’s costs might have varied?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation G: Original, Custom Newsletters for Standard Prices&lt;/strong&gt; ****&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert was a professional writer, not of screenplays or magazine articles, but of original custom newsletters. Despite his ability as a wordsmith in a range of contexts, the market consistently regarded him as a newsletter specialist and brought that business to him. Robert decided to embrace this reputation. The rationale behind his business model was simple: Give people what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He developed a business model that would always create original, authentic newsletters – best to maintain a credible connection between his clients and their readers – and in an apparent paradox, make profits charging standardized fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reputation for newsletters that had driven demand for his writing was based on reliably good writing with a degree of original authenticity that made his third-party authorship invisible. He trained and managed a small cohort of writers in his techniques also so that readers would assume the writing to be the issuer’s. Robert also ensured that each newsletter would have a look unique to the issuer. Then, each issue would be laid out with client-approved text and photos by the same person who designed the original template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert paid his writers and designers fixed fees and had them work under a contract that protected the business interests of all parties. Likewise, he charged his clients fixed fees under a purchase agreement that both encouraged decisive collaboration on newsletter contents and allowed the flexibility necessary to make each issue fulfil its potential as a timely reflection of the issuer-reader relationship. His purchase agreement even included a pay-upon-approval satisfaction guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1&lt;/strong&gt; If you could have original, custom work performed for you by a small team of creative people with the security of fixed fees and a satisfaction guarantee, would you bypass low-cost, off-the-shelf alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2&lt;/strong&gt; If you were to read a newsletter that seems to be a generic, impersonal product with the name and photo of an individual pasted in, would you consider it worth much more to that individual to issue an original, custom newsletter like those Robert and his team create?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Glenn R Harrington, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articulate.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Articulate Consultants Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glenn Harrington is the Principal Consultant of Articulate Consultants Inc. Since 1996 he has specialized in consulting on authentic key messages as the basis for effective marketing, brand management, and client loyalty.  []&lt;a href=&#34;href&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articulate.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articulate.ca/&#34;&gt;http://www.articulate.ca/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; []&lt;a href=&#34;href&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[]&lt;a href=&#34;href&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;][1] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articlesbase.com/&#34;&gt;ArticlesBase.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.articlesbase.com/management-articles/questioning-the-billable-hour-part-3-seven-industries-1543163.html&#34; title=&#34;Questioning the Billable Hour part 3: Seven Industries&#34;&gt;Questioning the Billable Hour part 3: Seven Industries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Never Bill by the Hour</title>
      <link>/why-i-never-bill-by-the-hour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 13:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>/why-i-never-bill-by-the-hour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve been reading my blog for any length of time, you know that I&amp;#8217;m an advocate of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0470275847/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0470275847&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=markrich0a-20&#34;&gt;Value-Based Fees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=markrich0a-20&amp;#038;l=as2&amp;#038;o=1&amp;#038;a=0470275847&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;. In a nutshell, here is the value proposition to the prospective client:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a cap on your investment. You know exactly what is to be spent and there are no surprises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is never a &amp;#8220;meter running.&amp;#8221; You do not have to worry each time my help is requested that I might be here for an hour, a day, or a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is unfair to you to place you in the position of making an investment decision every time you may need my help. Otherwise, you&amp;#8217;re trying to determine the impossible: Is this an issue that justifies a $2,000 visit or a $500 phone call. No client should ever be in that position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your people should feel free to use my assistance and to ask for my help without feeling they have to go to someone for budgetary approval. This only makes them more resistant to sharing their views, and at best delays the flow of important information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I find additional work that was unanticipated but must be performed, I can do it without having to come to you for additional funds. In those instances, legitimate, additional work would otherwise be viewed as self-aggrandizing and an attempt to generate addition hours or days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find additional, related work that must be done, you can freely request it without worry about increased costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall, set fee, in relation to the project outcomes to be delivered, is inevitably less of a proportional investment than hourly billing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If conditions change in your organization, you won&amp;#8217;t be in the difficult situation of having to request that the project be completed in less time. The quality approach is assured, since the fee is set and paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I decide that additional resources are necessary, there is no cost to you and I can employ additional help as I see fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the most uncomplicated way to work together. There will never be a debate about what is billable time (e.g., travel, report writing) or what should be done on site or off site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 0.7em;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining Value-Based Fees for Software Projects – Part 3</title>
      <link>/determining-value-based-fees-for-software-projects-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>/determining-value-based-fees-for-software-projects-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    I followed up on David Winch&amp;#8217;s last points with some more of my own:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Now, all I need is a few prospects on whom to practice! But I&amp;#8217;m sure &amp;#8216;how do I find clients?&amp;#8217; is a huge component of your workshop, so I do not presume to receive such a detailed response to that one.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;It is quite obvious to me now that I have been trying to sell not only what I do, but very specifically how I do it (right down to promoting my toolset of choice). I should probably be focusing more, if not entirely, on what I do to improve the client&amp;#8217;s condition. For example, &amp;#8216;improving small businesses through technology&amp;#8217; or some such tag line.&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    David replied:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m sure &amp;#8216;how do I find clients?&amp;#8217; is a huge component of your workshop&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;#8220;Actually, if I&amp;#8217;m understanding you correctly to mean &amp;#8216;how do I get enquiries and turn them into appointments and thus opportunities to get new clients&amp;#8217; then no, it isn&amp;#8217;t a component at all! The &amp;#8216;Pricing By Value&amp;#8217; Workshop only covers how to turn appointments into clients!&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Getting enquiries and turning enquiries into appointments are two other workshops which I&amp;#8217;ve run a few times but never had videoed. There&amp;#8217;s a bit of information on these subjects on my website and you could always decide to become one of my Coaching and Mentoring clients to find out more.&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Just to add a brief amount more for you, the key to both of these is the ability to articulate what you do, who you do it for, the pains people who need you are suffering, and how fantastic life is for them when you&amp;#8217;ve fixed their problem. This is also known as an elevator pitch! (Trying to anglicise this to «lift pitch» just doesn&amp;#8217;t seem right!). I’ve written a sheet on this subject which you may find useful.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;trying to sell not only what I do, but very specifically how I do it &amp;#8230; should probably be focusing more on what I do to improve the client&amp;#8217;s condition&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m so glad you realise this! You are the expert. That&amp;#8217;s why the client&amp;#8217;s called you in. They don&amp;#8217;t care how you do it, just fix it! Does the heart surgeon have to describe his procedures in detail in order to get asked to perform a triple by-pass?&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;improving small businesses through technology&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;You need to be communicating what I call &amp;#8216;Value Outcomes&amp;#8217; and this is a poor example of one! In my blog, last January, I wrote my analysis of value outcomes &amp;#8211; the good and the bad&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    I was back the next day:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Having an online discussion with a colleague of mine. He says &amp;#8216;Value-based billing doesn&amp;#8217;t produce quality either. Consultants are encouraged to do barely enough to meet the spec, and anything else gets the response of, Sorry, that&amp;#8217;s not in the spec, and we&amp;#8217;ll have to go through another round of estimation before we can even think about what to charge for that? If you stick with hourly, you can adjust the spec faster and be more flexible with the client.&amp;#8217;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;I can see some value in his claim. Anyone who&amp;#8217;s worked on a software project knows that change is inevitable. How do value-based fees deal with change without requiring everything to be knowable up front?&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Again, David was able to pass his ideas on to me:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Value-based billing doesn&amp;#8217;t produce quality either&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;I agree! Merely trying to introduce a culture of Value-Based Billing doesn&amp;#8217;t create quality. And besides, behaviour creates culture, not the other way around!&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s the way that Value-Based Billing is incorporated into the Sales Conversation and into the relationship that ensures quality, whatever that may mean in each individual case.&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;If you believe you are being abundantly rewarded for your efforts, you&amp;#8217;ll go that extra mile to please your client. You&amp;#8217;ll have an incentive to get better at your job, you&amp;#8217;ll be acting in yours and the client&amp;#8217;s best interests, and you&amp;#8217;ll be lining up the next project and the referrals too.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Consultants are encouraged to do barely enough to meet the spec&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Encouraged by whom? The client sees you&amp;#8217;re an expert amongst experts and that he&amp;#8217;s getting phenomenal value for his bargain investment, so he won&amp;#8217;t encourage it! And you, the Consultant, are getting hugely rewarded, so why do you feel a need to cut effort and &amp;#8216;quality&amp;#8217; to the bare minimum?&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Does the person who asked you the question equate &amp;#8216;value-based billing&amp;#8217; with &amp;#8216;bargain basement prices&amp;#8217;? If they do then I can see why they think this way. But they need educating into the true meaning of the term. Value-based pricing means Win-Win. And Win-Win means huge value return for bargain investment, coupled with hugely profitable reward. Both can and do co-exist if you use these methods.&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Unfortunately the expression &amp;#8216;value pricing&amp;#8217; has been hijacked by the &amp;#8216;cheap and cheerful&amp;#8217; brigade, so you need to make sure your meaning is correctly understood when you talk about Pricing By Value and Value-Based Pricing/Billing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;anything else gets the response of, &amp;#8216;Sorry, that&amp;#8217;s not in the spec, and we&amp;#8217;ll have to go through another round of estimation before we can even think about what to charge for that.&#39;&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Yes! The original project needs specifying, and anything that arises later that&amp;#8217;s not within the spec should be discussed separately as a potential additional chargeable project.&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Having said that, you shouldn&amp;#8217;t be discussing highly detailed first projects! As I said to you before, the first thing you suggest might be a research project to develop the detailed spec of the first coding project. You deserve to be paid for this initial investigation, and why not! If the client has already completed this exercise internally or with another consultant, won&amp;#8217;t you in any case want to check their work to date before you commit to what you&amp;#8217;ll do? When you fly your aircraft, do you give it an external visual inspection before you start the engine? I&amp;#8217;m not a pilot but I bet you do. Commercial pilots certainly do it, every time!&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;And of course you need to know about the new problem and the new circumstances before you can start to price the new project. This needs to be completed but, if it&amp;#8217;s closely related to the existing project, this needn&amp;#8217;t take a very long time.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;If you stick with hourly, you can adjust the spec faster and be more flexible with the client.&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Faster than what? More flexible than what? When you&amp;#8217;ve won a few projects on a value-based basis you&amp;#8217;ll be adept at doing all that needs to be done very rapidly.&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;In my Workshop I stress that you need to be able to handle the figures in your head, so they have to be simple. In fact I advocate (as does Alan Weiss) that you get to the point of doing it by gut feel and not computation. If you need to &amp;#8216;go away and work out the figures&amp;#8217;, or even use your calculator on the spot, you are screaming &amp;#8216;cost-based and time-based billing&amp;#8217;, so this would be a shot in the foot!&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;As for flexibility, you will know more than most people about all the circumstances surrounding the client&amp;#8217;s problem. Presented with a new requirement, your judgement of what is and isn&amp;#8217;t feasible and sensible will be considerable. Without this insight you&amp;#8217;ll just be reacting with knee-jerks, even if you charge for them. This would be sticking band-aids over symptoms, not addressing underlying diseases! What long-term use is it giving an aspirin to a brain tumour sufferer?&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Anyone who&amp;#8217;s worked on a software project knows that change is inevitable&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;True! As you and the client understand more about the problem and its solution, some ideas will be jettisoned and replaced. What&amp;#8217;s new?&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;If the scope of the project is to reach the end result, and not about the means to that end, it&amp;#8217;s all still within the scope of the project. And if you&amp;#8217;re being paid five times what your hourly-based fee would have been, what do you care if it extends a little? You just don&amp;#8217;t want to allow it to extend ad infinitum, aka scope creep.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;#8220;How do value-based fees deal with change without requiring everything to be knowable up front?&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;The real interesting one! And I think I&amp;#8217;ve already answered it! If extreme knowledge is needed to price the final project, you need introductory project(s) to discover that extreme knowledge. These can be priced from the knowledge available at the outset.&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t keep thinking in terms of one huge project! Some of the more complex projects need several stages. As Alan Weiss says when he&amp;#8217;s suggesting giving the client options, un-bundle your catch-all solution and re-bundle the components into different &amp;#8216;value packages&amp;#8217;. Again, on my Workshop, we look at the question of &amp;#8216;How will I be able to think of several &amp;#8216;value packages&amp;#8217;?&amp;#8217;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;ve not tried this next approach myself, but it strikes me that if the client is looking for a bid on an enormous project, you could suggest that they break it down into a series of slightly smaller ones. If you&amp;#8217;re worried about not getting the follow-on work, who else has a better relationship and is better placed to get it? I&amp;#8217;d suggest the follow-on work is yours to lose!&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    And there&amp;#8217;s still more!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;If I&amp;#8217;m not careful, I may end up writing another book here&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>