<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on Mark Richman</title>
    <link>https://markrichman.com/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on Mark Richman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. Mark Richman Consulting, Inc. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markrichman.com/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Your CFO Hates Me</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/2017/03/07/your-cfo-hates-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/2017/03/07/your-cfo-hates-me/</guid>
      <description>Your CFO hates my guts.
Well, not me personally; we’ve probably never met. But if he is anything like the CFOs at many of my client companies, he has reviewed the business case for a cloud migration and shot me a dirty look or two.
When working with tech execs on their cloud migration strategies, I find their CFOs often get involved early in the decision making process. This is a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Elastic Beanstalk &amp; Go</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/2017/02/17/aws-elastic-beanstalk-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/2017/02/17/aws-elastic-beanstalk-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to easily deploy a Go web application using AWS Elastic Beanstalk and Go.
  If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, AWS Elastic Beanstalk lets you deploy your app to AWS, and it takes care of load balancing and auto-scaling for you.
No server configuration required at all.
It’s cool because it supports lots of platforms - Java, PHP, .NET, Node.js, Python, Ruby, Docker, and Go.
I like working with Go</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming out of the closet with AWS</title>
      <link>https://markrichman.com/2017/01/25/coming-out-of-the-closet-with-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark@markrichman.com (Mark Richman)</author>
      <guid>https://markrichman.com/2017/01/25/coming-out-of-the-closet-with-aws/</guid>
      <description>Most of my clients come to me for help escaping the hell of managing servers in a closet somewhere in their office, or in a colocation facility. They realized their data was far too critical to leave on-premises, risking data loss and security breaches. What’s more, if they needed to rapidly scale their operations to meet demand, it would take weeks to add capacity. In terms of cost, maintaining infrastructure hardware and having to pay network engineers to keep it all going quickly erodes profits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>